JENNIFER BYRNES

Richmond, VA

Phone: 804 909-0707 | Portfolio: https://github.com/JenniferByrnes

Email: jennifer.byrnes@outlook.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jenniferkbyrnes/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a focus on front-end development and experience in application development, teaching, and military leadership. Expected certificate from the University of Richmond's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp in November 2022; skillset has been recently updated with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js, and responsive web design to build applications from scaffolding to rollout.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwinds, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, API Calls, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Wix, PeopleSoft, PowerBuilder, COBOL, PL1, C, UNIX, SQL

PROJECTS

Weather Playlist | <u>Deployed</u> | <u>Github</u> – a team project - given a location, the program returns a weather report, Spotify playlist link, and GIF based on the current weather. I led this project and did the HTML scaffolding, Bulma code, coded the weather API section.

MVC Tech Blog | <u>Deployed</u> | <u>GitHub</u> – a blog for tech fans to read blog posts. Authorized users can leave comments or add posts. This was a solo challenge using Sequelize, mySQL, Express, and Handlebars

What's Cooking | <u>Deployed</u> | <u>Github</u> - a personal cookbook. The user can see images of recipes, instructions, an ingredient list, and add notes. Logged in users can add/edit/delete recipes. I led a team of six to create it and did most of the initial coding, the integration of the back to front end piece and installed TailwindsCSS to it.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Programmer Analyst Capital One

2000-2002

Richmond, VA

Used knowledge of C, UNIX, SQL, and relational databases to maintain Capital One's Customer Disputes software and data.

Key Accomplishments:

• Led upgrade projects for the Disputes area including training two new programmers and directing programmers based overseas.

Programmer Analyst 1996-2000

Circuit City Stores Richmond, VA

Successfully implemented PeopleSoft Human Relations software conversion from PowerBuilder. Key Accomplishments:

• Technical lead of a 5 person team to switch existing Human Relations software from an existing PowerBuilder front end to PeopleSoft HR.

Systems Engineer 1991-1995

EDS various locations

Responsible for requirements gathering, analysis, design, specification, programming, and testing various parts of the EDS Medicaid systems in several states. Conducted end user training classes for the newly implemented Public Assistance program in Florida and documented the system for future projects. Coded in Unix shell scripts, PowerBuilder, COBOL, Informix

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Substitute Teacher Hanover County Schools 2016 - Pres.

Hanover County, VA

Frequently requested for long term positions teaching math and history at different Hanover middle schools. This included preparing lessons, developing teaching aides using newly installed Smartboards, tests, grading, parent communications. Well versed in Schoology, Google tools. Completed a full year of virtual teaching in 2020-2021 as Math 6 teacher.

United States Navy 1985 - 2007

Supply Corps Officer various locations

Served five years active duty first as a Disbursing officer in Greece and then as Disbursing/Sales Officer and then Food Services Officer on board the USS Cape Cod. 17 years in the Reserves focused on contracting and logistics. One year as a Commanding Officer.

- Received the Batchelder Award for Leadership.
- Achieved the rank of Commander.

EDUCATION

- ❖ Full Stack Development Bootcamp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA expected 11/2022
- ❖ A 24 week intensive program focused on gaining skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Node.js, Bulma, Bootstrap, Tailwinds, and Handlebars.
- Database Management and Object Oriented Analysis/Design: Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA
- ❖ Graduate class in Database Management
- Bachelor of Arts in Math/Computer Science: Emory University, Atlanta, GA